



Phone :+919705556988 | Email: venkatrajumakireddy1997@gmail.com | Tadepalligudem A.P

NAGA VENKAT RAJU MAKIREDDY

MyPortfolio: https://venkatm-portfolio-dev-ed.my.site.com/venkat-portfolio

Highly seasoned and accomplished Salesforce Developer with a strong record of client satisfaction with 5 years of experience. Team collaborator with strong verbal and written communication skills. Looking for opportunities to work on challenging projects with like-minded individuals to help fulfil organizational goals and expand my skills.

SKILLS :-

- > Backend: Apex, Apex Triggers, Asynchronous Apex.
- ➤ U.I: Lightning Components (Aura Components, LWC), Visual Force.
- ➤ Database: SOQL, SOSL.
- ➤ Automation: Flows, Process Builder, Workflow Rules, Validation Rules, etc.
- ➤ **Deployment**: Changesets, VS Code, Git, Metadata Deployment using Ant, SFDX.

EXPERIENCE

Accenture - System Engineer

FSL Consultant / Salesforce Developer Nov 2021 - Present

Project: 1 Vestas-Field Service(Dec 2021 - Nov 2023)

- Experience setting up field service features according to client unique business needs. This includes installing Field Service Lightning managed package and Field Service Lightning mobile app.
- ➤ Experience with setting up FSL data models (Work Orders, Service Appointments, Service Resources, Territories, etc).
- ➤ Ability to configure Service Rules and Objectives in support of Field Service business processes.
- ➤ Involved in Data Migration by using Data loader, Workbench.
- > Worked as Module Lead conducting SCRUM meetings and giving Knowledge Transition to newly joined associates.
- Experience in designing and developing Apex Classes, Controller Classes, extensions, and Apex Triggers for various functional needs in application.

Project: 2 Thames Water-Field Service Developer(Nov 2023- Present)

- Proficient in crafting and delivering diverse backlog user stories within designated sprint timelines to fulfill client needs effectively.
- > Actively involved in identifying and rectifying various bugs reported by end users in live production environments.
- > Played a pivotal role as a team lead, ensuring timely project delivery to clients and fostering team cohesion.

TCS Asst System Engineer

Salesforce Developer (July 2019 - May 2021)

Project -1: Bio Star Next Gen

- Developed Complex Business scenarios using Salesforce.com Out of box functionalities.
- Resolved the issues raised by testers on Salesforce CRM application.
- ➤ Achieved 94 percent plus code coverage for all Apex Test Classes.
- ➤ Migrated Code to production with various deployment tools like ANT, Change sets etc. and data with data loader of more than 20+k records.
- > Worked on Admin Tasks like Profiles and Permission sets, validation rules, Process Builder, Workflow rules etc.
- ➤ Having Knowledge in Integration API's.

Project -2 : Vaillant - Field Service

FSL Consultant /Salesforce Developer (May 2021 -Nov 2021)

- > Resolved the issues raised by testers on Field Service Application
- > Developed Complex Business scenarios using Salesforce.com Out of box functionalities on Field service application.

CERTIFICATIONS

- Salesforce Java Script Developer I
- > Salesforce Platform Developer II.
- > Salesforce Field Service Consultant.
- ➤ Salesforce Service Cloud Consultant.
- Salesforce Platform Developer 1.
- > Salesforce Certified Platform App Builder.
- Salesforce Administrator.

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Recognized thrice for best performance in Accenture.
- Received 3000 points for best performance
- Received Star Performer Award at TCS.
- Received Appreciation from client for moving code to Production.
- Earned 1000 badges in trailhead.salesforce.com.
- Received 1000 TC's gems for best performance.

EDUCATION

Sagi Ramakrishnam Raju Engineering College — B. Tech (IT) 2015 - 2019 with 81%

Aditya Junior College (Intermediate -MPC)

2013 - 2015 with 94%

ST. Jone's E.M School, Secondary School 2013 with 95%